A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy Program (EPP), Education and Research Division (E&R), Program Files FA633
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Benjamin F. Payton Files, 1968-1981; XXVIII
  - Benjamin F. Payton Report and Evaluation Files, 1970-1981; XXVIII.4
    - Review of Public Policy and Social Organization Program, Jan 19, 1981 (Box 58)
    - Problems and Opportunities in Governance and Economics, Mar 1979 (Box 58)
    - Communities and Neighborhoods -- A Possible Private Sector Intiative for the 1980s, Jan 2, 1979 (Box 58)
    - Education and Public Policy Committee Meeting Papers, 1972-1979 (Box 58)
    - The Arts Program, Mar 1980 (Box 58)
    - Comment on the Ford Foundation, Dec 1979 (Box 58)
    - Philanthropic Choices, Style and Methods -- a 25-Year Review, Mar 1976 (Box 58)
    - Program on Public Policy and Social Organization -- A Report to the Trustees, Sep 1975 (Box 58)
    - Proposed Budget FY 1978-1979, Jun 1977 (Box 58)
    - Midpoint Evaluation of Fellowship Program -- H. Challendor, 1977 (Box 58)
    - School Desegregation, 1977 (Box 58)
    - Minorities and Mathematics Conference, 1981 (Box 58)
    - CAEL -- College Potential Project, 1980 (Box 58)
    - Bell, Derrick A. -- School Desegregation: Constitutional Right or Obsolete Policy?, 1978 (Box 58)
    - Bell, Derrick A. -- School Desegregation: Constitutional Right or Obsolete Policy? -- Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 58)
    - Table and Sheets, 1978 (Box 59)
    - Evaluation -- Minority Program Planning Papers -- Communication, 1977-1978 (Box 59)
    - Evaluation -- Keeton -- CAEL -- Grant Working Papers, 1977 (Box 59)
    - Evaluation -- CAEL -- Minority Institutions Program -- Plans, 1976-1978 (Box 59)
    - Financial Analyses -- Project, 1978 (Box 59)
    - Financial Analyses -- 8 Institutions, 1977 (Box 59)
    - Edited Version -- Endowment Funding Reports, 1976 (Box 59)
    - Financial Analyses (Atlanta University Library), 1977 (Box 59)
    - "The Brown Decision, Pluralism, and the Schools in the 1980s" -- Remarks by Harold Howe II, Aug 1, 1979 (Box 59)
    - Meeting to Discuss Desegregation and Public Black Colleges -- Report, Mar 19, 1980 (Box 59)
    - Improving Education for Minorities -- Grant Recommendation (Box 59)
    - Conferences -- Miscellaneous Papers, 1978-1980 (Box 59)
    - Ford Foundation Board of Trustees -- Future Program Planning Project -- Directory of Selected Donors, 1976 (Box 59)
    - Speeches -- Harold Howe II, 1978-1980 (Box 59)
    - Conference on Minorities and Mathematics -- Transcripts -- Draft, Jul 8, 1980 (Box 59)
    - Report to the Ford Foundation on its Program of Assistance to Select Private Black Colleges, [1981] (Box 59)
    - Elsie M. Lewis, 1973 (Box 60)
    - Mary Williamson McHenry, 1973 (Box 60)
    - Black Colleges and the Continuing Dream -- Ford Foundation Reprint, 1976 (Box 60)
    - The Very Small College -- A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1976 (Box 60)
    - Minority Admissions and Performance in Graduate Study -- Ford Foundation Report, 1977 (Box 60)
    - Current Interests of the Ford Foundation, Jun 1980 (Box 60)
    - A Survey of Black American Doctorates, [1970] (Box 60)
    - Ford Foundation -- Applying for Grants -- Pamphlet, [1980] (Box 60)
    - Widening the Mainstream of American Culture -- A Ford Foundation Report on Ethnic Studies, Oct 1978 (Box 60)
    - Migration of American Negroes -- Report for the Ford Foundation, Apr 1968 (Box 60)
    - Financial Analyses -- Selected Black Colleges, 1978 (Box 60)
    - Underrepresentation of Minorities in Higher Education Meeting -- Memorandum, May 1977 (Box 60)
    - Ford Foundation Support for Private Black Colleges -- Interim Report, Mar 1976 (Box 60)
    - Race and Ethnicity Task Force Readings, Jun 1973 (Box 60)
    - Background Material -- Affirmative Action, Mar 1977 (Box 60)
    - Reforming the Economics of Public Education, Mar 1974 (Box 60)
    - International Studies Review -- A Staff Study, Sep 1979 (Box 60)
    - Analysing Endowment Funding and Case Studies of Selected Developing Institutions, Feb 29, 1976 (Box 60)
    - Economics of Helping the Poor, n.d. (Box 60)
    - Budgets, Assets and Expectations, Dec 1976 (Box 60)
    - Next Steps in Planning for the Foundation's Future, Sep 24, 1976 (Box 60)
    - A Response to the Trustees on Proposed Priorities, Special Questions, and Remaining Hard Choices, 1976 (Box 60)
    - Retrenchment of Management Costs -- Progress Report II, Mar 1976 (Box 60)
    - Retrenchment of Management Costs -- A Progress Report, Mar 1975 (Box 60)
    - Minorities and Mathematics Conference -- Report, 1981 (Box 60)
    - Education and Research Division -- Budget Alternatives for FY 1978-1979 -- Appendices, Mar 1977 (Box 60)
    - Bibliography of Holdings of the Civil Rights Documentation Project, 1974 (Box 60)
    - Research on Race and Ethnicity -- Reports on Federal (and some other) Agencies, Aug 1973 (Box 60)
    - Efficiency in Graduate Education -- An Attempted Reform, Jul 1977 (Box 60)
    - Graduate Education -- Internal Evaluation and Comments, 1977 (Box 60)
    - Federal Assistance to Minorities in Higher Education, 1976-1977 (Box 60)
- Legal Size, 1966-1975; XXIX
  - Survey of Black American Doctorates by James W. Bryant, Summer 1969-1975 (Box 61)
  - Select Committee on Higher Education in New York State -- Miscellaneous, 1966-1968 (Box 61)
  - Edward J. Meade -- Singapore Educational Television (ETV), 1968 (Box 61)
- Appendix A: Reports, 1967-1981
  - Coleman, Joan E.; Minorities and Mathematics, Apr 1981 (Report #019978)
  - Sullivan, Oona; Ford Foundation Conference on Minorities and Mathematics, 1980 (Report #019979)
  - Feldman, Marvin J.; Japanese-American Teacher Exchange Program, Jun 19, 1967 (Report #019980)